Power over Spice is power over all.
- Synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Imperial Diary. Year
10,191. Third comment.
The battle for Arrakis
took everyone by surprise.
There were no witnesses.
The Harkonnen operation
was perpetrated overnight,
without warning or declaration of war.
By morning, the Atreides were no more.
All died in the dark.
And the Emperor said...
nothing.
Since that night, my father
has not been the same.
Nor have I.
His inaction is difficult
for me to accept.
For, I know he loved Duke
Leto Atreides like a son.
But my father's always been guided
by the calculus of power.
This would not be the first time
the Harkonnens have done his dirty work.
In the shadows of Arrakis
lie many secrets...
but the darkest of them all may remain.
The end of House Atreides.
Sister, Father is dead.
Shouldn't you go back to the stars,
be with him?
I'm afraid I won't have enough time
to fix things before your coming.
This world is beyond cruelty.
Enemy.
Stay here.
Down. Right.
They're close.
Do you hear that?
The rats are calling a worm.
Worms!
Unit, climb. Now!
Look for wormsign.
We're okay.
Shields!
No Shields!
I got you, rat.
Never stand with your
back towards the open.
How many times do I have
to tell you that, huh?
You okay?
- Yeah.
- How 'bout her?
She's fine.
They do not usually venture this deep.
They wanna make sure
no Atreides escaped.
You think too much of yourself.
No, no, we are in the deep desert.
Only Fremen can survive here.
They were here for us, not for you.
Don't worry.
I'm taking you somewhere
they will never find us.
Filthy water.
It's full of chemicals, but
good enough for cooling systems.
Don't let it out.
- You okay?
- Mm-hmm.
Don't let that out.
Don't let it out!
- I'm okay.
- Are you sure?
Mm-hmm.
You fought well...
once you woke up.
I wasn't sleeping.
No, no, no. I'll do it.
Lor... Lord Rabban.
Now that the spice
fields have been secured,
I strongly recommend bringing all
troops out of Fremen territories.
We're losing too many men to the desert.
Rats.
- I beg your pardon?
- We're losing men to rats.
Fremen! I can't confirm, my Lord.
Communications are
hectic in the open sands.
Your orders were to
control the whole planet.
- We are.
- I see only half of it.
As you may recall,
the South is uninhabitable, my Lord.
May I suggest you get some rest?
Rats! Hairy rats!
Kill them! Kill them! Kill them all!
Kill them all!
Rats!
He's asking why we're so late.
He thinks you're spies.
You're not welcome here.
- He said...
- I got that.
- Thanks.
- Stay close to me. Hmm?
Sietch Tabr.
Jamis! Jamis!
You killed Jamis!
- Spies!
- Witch!
Stop! Stop!
They don't know what they're saying.
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
Mahdi!
Lisan al-Gaib!
I need your guidance
with the two foreigners.
Give them back to the desert.
I saw the signs.
Again.
Stilgar, your faith is
playing tricks on you.
The Lisan al-Gaib has
not shown his face yet!
He killed Jamis in a fair fight.
He speaks our language.
He will quickly learn our ways.
I'm ready to pledge my life for him.
The desert will handle his fate.
What about the woman?
Look how your Bene Gesserit
propaganda has taken root.
Some of them already
think I'm their messiah.
Others...
false prophet.
I must sway the non-believers.
If they follow me, we can
disrupt spice production.
That's the only way I
can get to the Emperor.
Your father didn't believe in revenge.
Yeah, well, I do.
What is happening?
Too spicy for the foreigner?
What is it?
There is spice in the food.
He'll look pretty with blue eyes.
Don't mock him.
He deserves our respect.
He's a good fighter.
Woman.
Come with me.
To the well,
our water we return.
We bless our brother, Jamis.
Thirty-eight million decaliters.
None of us, even dying of thirst,
would ever drink this water.
This is...
sacred.
Jamis' water.
We have a thousand such places.
When we have enough water,
the Lisan al-Gaib will
change the face of Arrakis.
He will bring back the
trees. He will bring back...
a Green Paradise.
So many souls.
Never give your water away,
not even for the dead. Hmm?
Why are you showing me this?
Because you are Bene Gesserit.
Because you understand the prophecies.
The mother of the Lisan al-Gaib
will be a Reverend Mother.
Our Reverend Mother is dying.
You want me to take her place?
Yes, I do.
You believe in Paul?
There are signs.
Yes.
What if I would refuse?
Mmm. Then, he's not Lisan al-Gaib,
and you have no purpose to serve.
What else is left to do then but
to return your water to the well?
Huh.
It's an honor, isn't it?
I think you should feel honored.
Well, it was a choice
between this or death,
so, you know, forgive
me if I'm not flattered.
How does one become a Reverend Mother?
It's different from
one culture to another.
Here on Arrakis, I have no idea.
You're afraid.
Reverend Mothers are tasked
with holding the memories
of all the Reverend Mothers
that came before them,
so I'll be given centuries
of pain and sorrow.
Is it dangerous?
It's lethal for men.
That's for sure.
What are you guys laughing about?
Don't bother.
You don't believe in all this?
No, we don't.
These are old Southern beliefs.
Southern beliefs?
Southern tribes believe a messiah
will come to deliver us from evil.
You don't believe in the Lisan al-Gaib?
We believe in Fremen.
Amen.
You want to control people, you
tell them a messiah will come.
- Mm-hmm.
- Then they'll wait for centuries.
Now, we must pray.
What about him?
- Stilgar?
- Mm-hmm.
He's from the South. You
didn't notice his accent?
What'll happen to my mother?
She'll drink worm piss.
Not funny.
He's about to lose her.
If she's stupid enough to drink poison.
Shut up! We are praying.
I must not fear.
Fear is the mind-killer.
Fear, the little death that
brings total obliteration.
I will face my fear. I will...
Here is the Water of Life.
It frees the soul.
If you drink...
you shall die.
you may see.
Drink!
What is it?
What have we done?
She is pregnant.
- That was no miracle!
- You saw it with your own eyes!
The Mother of the Lisan al-Gaib
shall survive the Holy Poison.
And She did.
As written!
Her people wrote that!
Blasphemy.
The prophecy has been accomplished.
The Mahdi must be Fremen!
Arrakis must be freed by its own people!
She's right. She's right!
It's no miracle.
My mother was trained to do that.
Poison transmutation is something
advanced Bene Gesserit can do.
I'm not the Mahdi.
I'm not here to lead.
I'm here to learn your ways.
Let me fight beside you.
That's all I'm asking.
The Mahdi is too humble
to say He is the Mahdi.
Even more reason to know He is!
As written!
How are you?
Better.
How is she?
She was frightened, but she's...
she's okay.
Paul.
She talks to me.
She believes in you.
She says...
Kwisatz Haderach, show us the way.
You're so close now.
Only one step remains and you
will become the Kwisatz Haderach.
Only one step remains.
You must do what I did.
You must drink the Water of Life.
And your mind, it's gon... it's
gonna open and you will see.
You will see!
The beauty and the horror!
If you wanna fight with us,
first thing, you must learn
to be one with the desert.
So, here is a tent and enough food.
I want you to cross that
small erg and come back.
Travel by night.
You know how to use a paracompass?
- Yes.
- Oh.
Anything else I should know?
Uh, beside the worms and the Harkonnens,
beware of the trapdoor spiders.
Centipedes are very
nasty. Not the big ones.
They are harmless.
But the little ones, you have
to worry about. And... Oh!
Don't ever, ever listen to the jinn.
- The jinn?
- Jinn.
Desert spirits.
They whisper at night.
They, they can possess you.
Really, be careful. They are demons.
But it's true. Don't listen to them.
He doesn't know how to cross.
Stilgar is going to get him killed.
What is he trying to prove?
What do you think?
"The Prophet shall know
the ways of the desert."
I think it's for the best.
What's this?
You care for him now?
He's not like the other strangers.
He's sincere.
Jamis.
You sandwalk like a drunk lizard.
Yeah, I'm doing pretty good so far.
Yeah, well, you're not
even in worm territory yet.
You have to break up your rhythm.
Like this.
Now, that's interesting because
in the filmbooks I've studied,
the anthropologists say, in
order to properly sandwalk,
you actually have...
Never mind. Please keep going.
You know, I'm the only one who believes
you're gonna make it until summer?
Everyone else thinks you
won't make it two weeks.
If you wanna follow us in the desert,
you need to know how windtraps work.
So, listen to me.
They're simple, but they
require constant attention.
Uh, this right here,
it captures the moisture
and then it carries it into that pocket.
Uh, and these are the filters.
They need to be changed
every three days.
What?
Stop looking at me like that.
He's training with the Fremen.
He will be back soon. Don't worry.
Mm-hmm.
You're right. If we want
to protect your brother,
we need all the Fremen to
believe in the prophecy.
We must convert the
non-believers one by one.
We need to start with the weaker ones.
The vulnerable ones.
The ones who fear us.
Hey, get out of here. Go.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Let's go! Move!
Load.
Chani!
Reload!
Ugh! Reload.
Oh, watch out!
Its shield will only open when it fires.
I know that. What do you
think I'm trying to do?
I'll trigger it. On my signal. Be ready.
Go!
Ah, shit!
Go! Go!
You saw what he did.
He saw it coming, and he saved her life.
He saw it.
He can foresee.
Muad'Dib likes his smell.
Who taught you to fight like that?
- My old masters.
- Hmm.
They were close friends.
They were massacred.
Alongside my father.
You've been fighting the
Harkonnens for decades.
My family's been fighting
them for centuries.
I know everything about them. Their
habits, their ways of thinking.
You know everything about the desert.
You harness the very power of it.
We can stop them together, bury
them in the sand where they belong.
So that this planet
can be yours once more.
What would you have us do? Huh?
What would you do, Stilgar?
I? I would... would
strike even further north.
Then I will go further north.
And the further north you go,
the more likely it is you die.
Then I'll die.
Maybe you will too.
But the others will keep going.
And they won't stop
until the Fremen are free.
He deserves to be Fedaykin.
He needs names, Stilgar.
He does!
I see strength in you.
Like Usul.
The base of the pillar.
Come, come.
You shall be know among us as Usul.
- Usul.
Usul. And now, a Fedaykin is a fighter
and needs a war name.
You must choose.
How do you call the, uh...
The small desert mouse, again?
- Muad'Dib?
- Muad'Dib.
No, no, no.
Muad'Dib is wise in
the ways of the desert.
Muad'Dib...
creates his own water.
The constellation that points to
the North Star, we call Muad'Dib.
"The One Who Points the Way."
That is a powerful name.
Now you are our brother. Mmm.
Paul Muad'Dib Usul.
Muad'Dib Usul.
Muad'Dib Usul. Mm.
Muad'Dib.
Usul.
Hey! Stilgar!
Father, I found my way.
It's breathtaking.
Hmm.
Look. Right there. Spice.
Arrakis is so beautiful
when the sun is low.
Where you're from, does water
really fall from the sky?
Oh, hm, yes.
Sometimes it rains for weeks on Caladan.
Where you see sand here, imagine water.
Our castle stands on
cliffs high above the sea.
If you dive in, you
can't reach the bottom.
- You dive in?
- Yes, it's called swimming.
I don't... I don't believe you, Usul.
Usul.
What's your secret name?
Sihaya.
- Sihaya.
- Hmm.
What does that mean?
Means Desert Spring.
"Desert Spring."
- I love it.
- I hate it.
It's from some stupid prophecy.
I prefer Chani.
I prefer Chani, too, then.
Do you think Stilgar would teach me?
- To ride?
- Yeah.
No. Only Fremen ride worms.
Well, I thought I'd
become one, didn't I?
By name, not by blood.
Your blood comes from
Dukes and Great Houses.
We don't have that here.
Here, we're equal, men and women alike.
What we do, we do for
the benefit of all.
Well, I'd very much
like to be equal to you.
Paul Muad'Dib Usul...
maybe you could be Fremen.
Maybe I'll show you the way.
Rabban.
Fremen attacks on your watch.
Your orders were to restore
spice production to full capacity.
Do you know what it means if you fail?
The Emperor will take
spice out of our control.
Tighten your grip, Rabban.
Uncle.
Or feel mine on your neck.
Usul? Usul.
It's okay. It's okay.
Hey.
I'm here, I'm here.
It's been a while since you've
had one of those nightmares.
Mm.
Tell me, what was it about?
Nothing's clear. It's only fragments.
I'm in the South, and
I'm following someone.
And it triggers a holy war.
Millions and millions of
people starving to death...
because of me.
You've been exposed to
spice for a long time.
It can create weird dreams.
It's a big day.
We can ask Stilgar to call it off.
No. I'm fine.
Usul.
I tuned it myself.
- Here.
- Thanks.
Don't try to impress anyone.
You are brave. We all know that.
Heh? Be simple.
Be direct. Nothing fancy.
- Nothing fancy.
- Hey, I'm serious.
Nothing fancy or you
will shame my teaching.
I won't shame you. I understand.
Shai-Hulud decides today if you
become Fremen, or if you die.
Hey, Muad'Dib!
Don't embarrass us!
Call a big one!
Don't worry.
Stilgar taught him well.
Enough joking.
This is the final test.
Lower.
Okay. Okay.
Not that big.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. Okay!
Come on!
Whoa!
You're a rider!
As written.
Reverend Mother!
Muad'Dib made peace with Shai-Hulud.
He called a grandfather worm.
The biggest ever seen.
As written!
Shai-Hulud shall bow
to the Boy from the Outer World.
Bless the Maker and His works.
Will not Shai-Hulud know
the Mahdi when He comes?
Then share the Word.
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm. I know they do.
Our task in the North is nearly done.
They believe in Paul.
Now we go South.
There are millions of
fundamentalists there.
They will protect him when he comes.
The Kwisatz Haderach
will be born in the South.
Will you always be with me?
As long as I breathe.
What's wrong?
- Chani.
- There will be trouble.
What are you talking about?
Chani, what do you mean?
The way they look at you.
They worship you now.
The Fedaykin, they count your victories.
They say you can see the future.
Whisper, "Lisan al-Gaib."
I'm no messiah.
I'm a Fedaykin of Sietch Tabr.
Yet, we have a Bene Gesserit among us,
fanning the flames of your legend,
saying you're the One.
Mm.
Reverend Mother!
Your palanquin is ready!
She says you should be coming with us.
You know I can't.
She's asking why.
Because I must continue
fighting in the North,
to protect you down there in the South.
She says she can tell when you lie.
Tell her that's because our mother
keeps spreading dangerous tales.
What is she saying now?
She says you're blinded by love,
and she reminds you that
you must reserve your hand
for the most strategic alliance.
She's also wondering why you
don't believe in who you are.
I do believe.
I believe I matter to these people.
And I believe I'm making
a difference in this war.
We're nearly at the gates of the city.
- That's not what she means.
- I know what she means.
Do you not think I also feel
the weight of the prophecy?
It's not a prophecy.
It's a story that you keep telling,
but it's not their story, it's yours.
They deserve to be led
by one of their own.
What your people did to
this world is heartbreaking.
We gave them something to hope for.
That's not hope!
Reverend Mother,
we have to go!
I'll be waiting for you.
All of us.
Those storms look bad.
They're the Guardians of the South.
It's a hard crossing,
but Shai-Hulud is strong.
- How much?
- We lost...
eighty percent of our last crop.
My Lord Rabban, you should not
leave the security perimeter.
Security perimeter? The
rats are already inside.
The Fremen Demon might be with them.
I hope so.
We're tracking them, my Lord.
Today, Muad'Dib dies!
The rats are travelling fast.
Move!
Where is he?
Still negative, my Lord.
Why do I have to do everything myself?
Open range!
Range open.
Life. Delta, delta, delta.
I've lost them.
- Strike!
- Yes, my Lord.
Muad'Dib!
Show yourself!
Muad'Dib! Muad'Dib! Muad'Dib!
For Muad'Dib!
Muad'Dib.
Some new Fremen prophet?
It's not the first time
we've had frictions with the Fremen.
None of this magnitude.
So, my dear daughter...
how would you deal with this prophet?
If this Muad'Dib is a religious figure,
you can't use direct force.
Repression only makes
a religion flourish.
You'll only end up humiliating yourself.
You underestimate my Sardaukar.
You underestimate the power of faith.
Her Highness proves once again
that she was my most acute student.
- You'd send assassins?
- No.
Prophets get stronger when they die.
Let the conflict on
Arrakis turn into war.
You then bring peace. As a savior.
You'd be a formidable empress.
Muad'Dib. The prophet.
The one who points the way.
These are our own religious
patterns, aren't they?
This is our doing.
Muad'Dib means kangaroo mouse.
An unusual war name for a Fremen.
- What if Paul Atreides were still alive?
- Enough!
This must not come out. Even to
your father's ears. Understand?
I do, Reverend Mother.
If Paul is alive, he
likely knows the truth.
And should the Great Houses learn
that your father was behind
the liquidation of the Atreides,
your father will face
war and lose the throne.
Then what hope is there?
Hope?
We are Bene Gesserit.
We don't hope, we plan.
Paul is not our only prospect.
The Baron's youngest nephew,
Feyd-Rautha Harkonnen,
will inherit Arrakis.
He may be the answer.
Feyd-Rautha? He's psychotic.
That's irrelevant.
The question is, can we control him?
And I intend to find out.
Would you like some
fresh meat, my darlings?
Lungs? Or liver?
What would you like? I
hear they're big today.
Your new blades for
this very special day,
na-Baron, Feyd-Rautha.
A notch off balance.
It's the tip.
Should be sharper.
Come.
I won't die like a fool.
Kill me now.
No drug for you today, Atreides.
Under our glorious black sun,
we welcome to these special festivities
our beloved leader
Baron Vladimir Harkonnen.
His presence today, watching over
a spectacle of blood and honor,
marks the Holy Birthday of our
beloved na-Baron, Feyd-Rautha.
Welcome to Giedi Prime, sisters.
I hope your travels were agreeable.
A long way to come just
to watch our prospect
risk his life, Lady Fenring.
No fear.
These fights are all for show.
But we'll get a good look at him.
Feyd-Rautha! Feyd-Rautha!
In celebration of our
na-Baron Feyd-Rautha,
we present a special treat.
The last three specimens
of House Atreides.
That slave isn't drugged.
That bug is walking straight.
You should cancel the fight.
Don't spoil my nephew's birthday.
Happy birthday, dear nephew.
Why do they not stop the fight?
Plans within plans.
Show me who you are.
There he is.
Back! Back!
Stay back!
You have fought well, Atreides.
Hmm.
Feyd-Rautha! Feyd-Rautha!
He's impressive, indeed.
The slave wasn't drugged.
You tried to kill me.
This morning you were a playboy,
feared and envied,
but tonight you're a hero.
My gift to you.
I ought to drown you in that tub.
Don't be hasty.
I have another gift for you.
A bigger one.
Arrakis.
What about Rabban?
He has failed to
protect spice production.
Rabban will be reassigned.
Tame Arrakis, Feyd.
Free the spice. I'll make you Emperor.
Emperor?
How?
The Emperor helped me
destroy the Atreides.
He lent his own army to the cause.
A serious crime.
If it came to light, the Great
Houses would rise against him.
And then...
who will sit on the throne?
Feyd-Rautha Harkonnen.
You're following me.
Am I?
I may have gotten lost.
Will you show me the way out
of this maze, my Lord na-Baron?
We've met, haven't we?
I don't think so.
I'm Lady Margot Fenring.
I'm here to honor your coming of age.
You're not allowed in this section.
How did you get past the guards?
The guards?
May I ask, what are you doing here?
You're not taking part
in your own celebrations?
You're Bene Gesserit.
And what makes you say that?
I remember now.
I dreamed about you last night.
A pleasant dream, I hope.
Don't mock me, woman.
I wouldn't dare.
I know your Bene Gesserit tricks.
And what do you know
about the Bene Gesserit?
Tell me.
Something wrong?
I don't recognize this place.
This is the guest wing.
Where are you going?
To my room.
Come. To. Me.
Kneel.
Put your right hand in the box.
A sociopath. Of high intelligence.
Driven. Cruel.
But strongly motivated by honor.
He yearns to be hurt.
He loves pain.
Can he be redeemed?
He can be controlled.
He's sexually vulnerable.
And?
The bloodline is secured.
Female, as you requested.
You did well, Margot.
Respectfully, why didn't
you test him yourself?
I'm a motherly figure.
And based on what happened
between him and his own mother,
I didn't expect to be effective.
What happened between
him and his mother?
He murdered her.
Desire and humiliation.
Those are his levers.
If Feyd-Rautha prevails on Arrakis,
we shall know how to control him.
All hail na-Baron Feyd-Rautha!
The new Planetary Governor of Arrakis!
Rid me of this Fremen Demon.
Feyd-Rautha! Feyd-Rautha!
Feyd-Rautha!
♪ Do away with these idiots ♪
♪ I blame ♪
♪ My stillsuit is full of piss ♪
♪ My hand is caked in sand ♪
♪ Save me from these utter morons ♪
♪ Another world, another land ♪
We're in.
Juicy?
Juicy, juicy.
Well, it was nice knowing ya.
Oh, yeah?
Radar's clear. We're clear.
Cooking time.
Juicy, juicy.
Yeah, I got a meter reading...
All right, guys, worms are on their way.
- Watch out for abrasions.
- Get ready to dock.
It's gonna get hot.
Crank 'em up! Throw them up!
Hold!
Mine! Mine!
Get moving!
- East! East!
- Get clear!
Let's get out of here!
Incoming!
Don't run, fight!
We're in deep Fremen shit.
Holy Mother.
Oh, fuck.
I recognized your footsteps...
- old man.
- No.
You young pup.
You young pup!
Mmm. After the Battle of Arrakeen,
I was able to negotiate a trip
back home for the survivors.
Thanks to these guys.
Why'd you stay?
Well, I wanted blood.
Rabban's head?
Mm-hmm.
Well, since Muad'Dib's
been driving Rabban crazy,
the smuggling business
has been quite profitable.
Gurney Halleck the smuggler.
Paul Muad'Dib.
I've heard many stories about Muad'Dib.
None of them pretty.
You see the fear?
When our resources are limited...
fear is all we have.
How many men with you?
- Two hundred.
- Two hundred?
Do you realize what you're
able to achieve with 200 men?
Incredible fighters.
Duncan said there were millions of them.
In the Deep South, yes.
Well, what are you waiting for?
With thousands of these guys,
you could take control
of the entire planet.
It's your father's dream.
What are you afraid of?
Hey!
Worship, Gurney.
They used to be friends.
Now they're followers.
Muad'Dib, the Prophet.
Why is that a bad thing? Use it.
It's not that simple.
You have the power to avenge your
father, and you're afraid to use it?
Spice opened my mind, Gurney.
I can foresee things.
If I go South, all my
visions lead to horror.
Billions of corpses
scattered across the galaxy.
All dying because of me.
Because you lose control.
Because I gain it.
That's a lot of water.
Chani.
What? Look at him, he's hopeless.
He's family.
Really?
What do you think of the outsider?
I think he's trouble.
No, I trust Usul.
No need to be a prophet
to see what's ahead.
Your path leads to war.
You know that.
So, war is coming.
What will you do when you
feel its breath upon your neck?
If you don't want to
raise an army in the South,
you may still have an option.
Fire power...
which you don't have.
And here I am.
I know where your father
hid the family atomics.
Every House possesses an atomic arsenal.
I thought ours had been lost.
It's huge, Chani. It
could change everything.
I could aim the bombs
at the main spice fields.
He who can destroy a thing
has the real control of it.
So, you can control it and not us?
You promised me you didn't want power.
No matter what I do,
you still don't trust me.
'Cause you're a foreigner.
Like your friend.
I'm not a foreigner.
Not to me.
But to the desert, you are.
My allegiance is to you.
To the Fremen.
I'm doing this for all of us.
Do you believe me?
I'll talk to Stilgar.
There.
It's right under everybody's noses.
Not clever.
That's the idea.
Nobody would ever look in
there because it's obvious.
Not clever.
Did you find it?
I didn't look for it.
How many heads exactly?
Enough to blow up the whole planet.
It's a figure of speech.
You know what I mean.
Only with your genetic heritage.
Your great-great- grandfather's legacy.
The 92 original Atreides
family's atomic warheads.
Now that, that is power.
Imperial Diary. Year 10,191.
Eighth comment.
Reports from the south
of Arrakis arrive rarely.
These are barren, burnt
lands hidden by sandstorms
which stretch a thousand
miles across the equator.
Nothing can live there without faith.
Which is why our Bene
Gesserit missionaries
have been so productive there.
Through them, we are receiving
reports of a mysterious figure
taking grip on the imaginations
of the Southern fundamentalist tribes.
A new Reverend Mother from the North...
spreading word of the imminent
arrival of the Lisan al-Gaib,
"The Voice from the Outer World."
With religious fervor
rising in the South,
and Muad'Dib strangling
spice production in the North,
everything points to
the escalation of war.
Only one at a time...
or they fight each other to death.
How old?
Very young.
Hmm.
My daughter asks, how is it done?
Quiet.
The Water of Life.
Listen carefully.
Soon a man is going to visit your temple
and he may want you
to perform the rites.
Reverend Mother, it is forbidden.
You question the prophecy?
No man will survive.
Let him try!
What the hell?
Chani!
Chani.
Sietch Tabr.
Old fashioned artillery.
Genius.
We're literally melting
rock on their heads.
I want to go on the
ground. Prepare my troops.
My Lord. I would recommend
you stay inside. There was...
Bring his body to my quarters.
My poor darlings are hungry.
There was no food for
them on the flight.
What are you doing here?
It's early morning.
Kiss my feet, brother.
I'm gonna eviscerate your...
You humiliated our family.
You humiliated me.
Kiss...
or die.
We're even now.
Embarrass our family one more time...
it will be the last.
They're all dead!
I lost them all in the fire!
They didn't even engage on the ground,
like honorable fighters.
The whole of the North has been hit.
There is a call for a
war council in the South.
Every leader must attend.
Muad'Dib, they're waiting for you.
Usul, in the South...
only leaders are allowed to speak.
- You must take my place.
- I can't do that.
It is a good time to
cross blades with me.
I am weak. I am an easy kill, Muad'Dib.
I'd rather cut off my own hand.
We need you. We need the Lisan
al-Gaib to lead our people.
You know what I think
of all that, Stilgar.
I don't care what you
believe. I believe.
I didn't see it coming.
The Harkonnens aren't done here.
They just went back to reload.
We're setting thumpers.
We're moving everyone to the South.
I'll stay behind and cover your retreat.
- What are you talking about?
- Chani, I can't go with you.
You know why.
- I'll stay, too.
- Nobody stays but me.
- Paul.
- That's an order, Gurney Halleck! Go South!
Protect my mother.
- My Lord.
- Muad'Dib.
None of these people
will leave without you.
I can't go South.
He's afraid of the fundamentalists.
And he should be.
Don't resist.
Talk to me, Jamis.
You see only fragments.
You cannot see the future
without seeing the past.
To unlock your mind, you need
to drink the Water of Life...
and you will see everything.
A good hunter always climbs the
highest dune before his hunt.
He needs to see...
as far as he can see.
You need to see.
You must drink the Water of Life.
Your mind, it's gonna open,
and you will see.
The world has made choices for us.
If I go South, I might lose you.
You will never lose me,
Paul Atreides.
Not as long as you stay who you are.
I'll cross the storms with you.
Go South.
Bring your people to safety.
And then I will do what must be done.
Where?
Spy. Left behind.
No trace of the others.
They've gone South
to hide in the storms.
Send this message to the Baron.
The North is liberated and secured.
Harvest spice at will.
Yes, na-Baron.
You killed nine of my
men with one single blade.
She won't talk.
Tell her that's fine.
I already know
everything I need to know.
Only pleasure remains.
You're not allowed in here, stranger.
Leave or die.
I should be welcomed...
If you drink, you shall die.
If you drink, you may see.
Now that you can see our past,
you can see your future.
Oh, brother, my dearest brother,
you are not prepared
for what is to come.
You'll now learn the
truth about our family.
And it will hurt you to the core.
Paul...
Don't worry. I'm with you.
I love you.
Who knows about this?
Only you, Reverend Mother.
Good.
Here are the others?
They just arrived from the North.
Find them.
Paul?
Paul.
I'm here. I'm here. Hey.
What happened?
He's dead.
His vital signs are so
low, they can't be detected.
But he's alive.
What did you do to him?
No, not that. Why would he do that?
Why would you do that?
Because He is the One.
The Lisan al-Gaib should find His
way to where no man has ever been.
You're insane!
Chani, his body is fighting the
poison and he needs your help.
You do it.
You did this to him.
You did this to your own son!
You do it!
Fix it yourself.
Chani, you might not believe in the
prophecy, but you're a part of it.
You're the poison.
You and your lies.
Why would you do this?
Do it.
He shall come back
from the dead with Desert Spring tears.
Bring me a drop of Water of Life.
As written.
Desert Spring tears.
Kwisatz Haderach,
climb up. Arise.
Usul, I'm here. I'm here.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Are you sure?
Thanks to you.
I'm sorry about Chani.
She'll come to understand.
I've seen it.
You can see?
The visions are clear now.
I see possible futures. All at once.
Our enemies are all around us.
And in so many futures, they prevail.
But I do see a way.
There is a narrow way through.
I saw our bloodline, Mother.
Written across time.
You are the daughter of
Baron Vladimir Harkonnen.
Did my father know?
I didn't know myself, until
I took the worm's poison.
We're Harkonnens.
So this is how we'll survive.
By being Harkonnens.
We must talk.
Stilgar, you can stop
this. Do you hear me?
You have the power to stop this.
Northern woman!
You are not allowed to
speak inside the circle.
If you want to speak,
you know what to do.
Stilgar, please. For Arrakis' sake.
This prophecy is how they enslave us!
How they dominate...
You'll get yourself in trouble.
This is none of your business.
Rabban Harkonnen
himself killed my family.
He gave me this scar to remember him by.
This is all of my business.
Only tribe leaders can speak.
If you wish to share your voice,
you must take his place by defeating him
and returning his water to the well.
You think I'm stupid enough to
deprive myself of the best of us?
Do you smash a knife before battle?
Take my life, Usul.
It is the only way.
I'm pointing the way!
Slow down.
There is no one in this room
who can stand against me!
Your mothers warned you about my coming!
Fear the moment.
But you think you could have a chance.
But you're afraid.
What if I could be the One?
This could be the moment you've
been praying for, all your life.
You're praying now, to your grandmother.
She died nine moons ago.
She lost an eye.
A rock smashed her face as
she was crossing the Belt.
She was 12 when it happened.
At that time, this
world had a Fremen name.
Dune.
Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
In your nightmares, you
give water to the dead,
and it brings joy to your heart!
Muad'Dib!
Muad'Dib.
Mahdi, what do you foresee for us?
Green Paradise.
Lisan al-Gaib, show us the Way!
This is my father's ducal signet.
I am Paul Muad'Dib Atreides,
Duke of Arrakis.
The Hand of God be my witness!
I am the Voice from the Outer World!
I will lead you to paradise!
Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
Paul Atreides is still alive.
He challenges my father.
You've never been on Arrakis.
It's quite impressive. You'll see.
Was this all upon your advice?
What?
Did you counsel my father
to exterminate the Atreides?
Of course I did. Why else
would it have happened?
You tried to sacrifice
an entire bloodline.
And I was right to do it.
The Kwisatz Haderach is a form of power
that our world has not yet seen.
The ultimate power.
For ninety generations,
we have supervised House Atreides.
They were promising, but they
were becoming dangerously defiant.
Their bloodline had to be terminated.
That is why we have put
many bloodlines at work.
Several prospects.
But it's backfired.
Paul is alive.
And if he defeats
Feyd-Rautha, my father...
Your father will lose the
throne no matter who prevails.
But there is one way your
family can remain in power
and, through you, the
continuation of our stewardship.
One. Way.
Are you prepared?
You've been preparing me my
whole life, Reverend Mother.
You're heading north with the others?
I'm Fedaykin.
I follow my leaders. If
fighting goes north, I go north.
Paul didn't have a choice, Chani.
I won't be fighting for him.
I'm fighting for my people.
I came to wish you best of luck.
I'd wish you the same,
but it seems you've won your battle.
He took the bait.
Oh, the Emperor's very obliging.
He's right on time.
As you foresaw, Muad'Dib...
a great-grandmother of a storm.
What is he doing here?
I brought spice
production under control.
What do we do?
Send messages to the Great Houses.
Tell them that Arrakis
is under Sardaukar attack.
Tell them, their future
hangs in the balance.
He brought his whole army.
When the storm hits this ridge,
Gurney will open the
way for you, Stilgar,
so you can enter the basin from the West
and distract their defense systems.
Chani, I want you and your Fedaykin
to then attack from the East,
inside the basin.
I'll strike from the North, head on,
with the Fundamentalist troops.
And I'll serve Arrakeen for dessert.
Remember, I need the Emperor alive.
Long live the fighters.
Hm.
Baron,
do you have any idea who
this Muad'Dib could be?
Some fanatic, your
Majesty. That's all we know.
More. More. Give me more.
He's a madman!
- Mad?
- All Fremen are mad.
That's all you know?
Really?
Muad'Dib is dead.
Or he went hiding in the Southern storms
which means the same thing.
- They speak the truth.
- Your Majesty,
the sand storm that's approaching
threatens the integrity of our shields.
We recommend going back into orbit.
Well, the mountains will
protect us from most of it,
your Majesty.
Baron, have you ever investigated
the south regions of Arrakis?
Well, the entire
region is uninhabitable.
It's well known, your Majesty.
Your uninhabited South
exhibits evidence of human activity.
I wasn't aware of this.
I swear to you, I wasn't
aware of any of this.
Muad'Dib is alive.
I must find him.
Long live the fighters!
Fire!
Sardaukar! On guard!
Sardaukar!
Grandfather.
You die like an animal.
Muad'Dib.
Bring the prisoners to the Residency.
Kill the Sardaukar.
Give the Baron's body to the desert.
Rabban!
Look who's back from the dead.
For my Duke, and my friends.
Warships.
The Great Houses.
Gurney, it's time. Bring the prisoners.
My Lord.
This isn't over yet.
I want you to know...
I will love you as long as I breathe.
There is a massed armada in orbit.
You're facing a full invasion, Fremen.
How can you be so sure the
Great Houses are here for me?
They may be curious to hear my
side of the story, don't you think?
I am Paul Atreides, son of
Leto Atreides, Duke of Arrakis.
- Gurney.
- My Lord.
Send a warning to all ships.
If the Great Houses attack,
our atomics will
obliterate all spice fields.
- You're out of your mind.
- He's bluffing.
Consider what you're
about to do, Paul Atreides.
Silence!
Abomination.
Message sent, my Lord.
As a servant of the Imperium,
you will bow at my feet.
Your feet? You'll be
lucky to keep your head.
I'll take the hand of your daughter.
She will remain safe.
And we will rule
together over the Empire.
But you...
You have to answer for my father.
Do you know why I killed him?
Because he was a man
who believed in the rules of the heart.
But the heart is not meant to rule.
In other words...
your father was a weak man.
Stand or choose your champion.
I am here, Atreides.
I need a blade.
Accept mine.
Do not stain your hands on this animal.
Let me deal with him.
It's my burden, Gurney.
Why does he take such risks?
Muad'Dib leads the way.
I'm happy to finally meet you, cousin.
Cousin? Is that right?
Well, you wouldn't be the
first relative I've killed.
May thy knife chip and shatter.
She's your pet?
Any special attention for the pet?
You have fought well, Atreides.
Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
You should've believed.
You chose the wrong side.
Side?
You, of all people, should know.
There are no sides... Reverend Mother.
The life debt has been paid.
Spare my father now and I
will be your willing bride.
The throne will be yours.
My Lord, the Great Houses have answered.
They refuse to honor your ascendancy.
We await your orders, Lisan al-Gaib.
Lead them to Paradise.
Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
What is happening, Mother?
Your brother attacks the Great Houses.
The Holy War begins.
- Synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -